Ivan J. Zapata-Rivera

(551) 666-8559 | ivanzapatarivera@ivanzapatarivera.com | New Jersey

Portfolio https://ivanzapatarivera.com/

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivanzapatarivera/

GitHub https://github.com/ivanzapatarivera

GCP Associate Cloud Engineer (GCP ACE certified), CCAI, MERN Stack Web Developer and Data Analyst with a professional certificate from Rutgers University and a background designing with a cloud first approach, mobile first responsive apps using React, JavaScript (ES6 and Vanilla), REST API, and HTML5, and repositories. Deployed cloud and app back-end solutions supported by MongoDB, Node.js, and Python. Broad professional experience in project management and leading teams of over 200 employees.

Skills

- Certifications: GCP Associate Cloud Engineer, Scaled Agile (renewal in-progress)
- Frontend: React JS, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript (ES6 and Vanilla), jQuery, JSX, Dialogflow CX
- Backend: REST API, Axios, Node.js, Express, NoSQL, SQL, ORM, GCP Cloud Functions, App Engine
- Interpersonal: Communication, Teamwork, Problem Solving, Troubleshooting, Planning, Detail-Oriented

Projects

Speakeasy | Google, March 2021 - May 2022

- Launch in house messaging CCAI framework and voice applications.
- Technologies: Node.js, Python, Java, APIs, Cloud SDK, Google Dialogflow CX

Service Now & Jira CCAI | Multiple Clients, May 2022 - Present

- Develop and test voice and messaging CCAI client applications to set up time and expense inquiries.
- Technologies: Node.js, Python, InContact FW, AWS, Jira SM, Google Dialogflow CX, GCP Cloud Functions

Experience

TEK Systems, CCAI Developer & DAI, Dallas, TX, March 2021 - Present

- Create, develop and test Dialogflow voice and messaging applications.
- Automated development and testing of applications using Python and Node.js.
- Test APIs and debug fulfillment requests using continuous integration and delivery (CICD).

United Airlines, Inflight Services, Newark, NJ, May 2012 - Present

- Create operation performance reports, design pilot programs, testing and implementation of best practices.
- Review and discuss operation performance with local, national and international leadership.
- Face daily requirements, and develop fast and efficient solutions across functional teams and customers.

Santander Puerto Rico, Rules and Procedures Officer, San Juan, PR, June 2009 - April 2012

- Plan, design and implement proposals for internal customers to increase efficiency and revenue resulting in lowering costs and time consumption.
- Measure performance and customer service in front-office and back-office procedures.
- Ensure policies and procedures are documented, maintained and improved to meet regulations and business goals.

Education

- Rutgers University, New Jersey, Full Stack Flex Certificate
- Polytechnic University of Puerto Rico, MBA in International Enterprises and BBA in Management